<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Rakshan&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Rakshan&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Wi-Fi Attack and Defense Toolkit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wifi-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wifi-toolkit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;designing-a-wi-fi-offensive-and-defensive-toolkit&#34;&gt;Designing a Wi-Fi Offensive and Defensive Toolkit&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share a project that blends offensive hacking, defensive monitoring, and wireless protocol mastery—a &lt;strong&gt;Wi-Fi Offensive and Defensive Toolkit&lt;/strong&gt; built entirely in &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;. This toolkit is designed for both ethical hackers and cybersecurity learners who want to explore real-world Wi-Fi vulnerabilities and defenses in one unified platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-i-built-this-toolkit&#34;&gt;💡 Why I Built This Toolkit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increasing use of Wi-Fi in critical environments—hospitals, businesses, homes—comes with a growing attack surface. Sadly, most users and even professionals underestimate how vulnerable Wi-Fi truly is. I created this project to:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rhcsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rhcsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;im-officially-a-red-hat-certified-system-administrator-rhcsa&#34;&gt;I’m Officially a Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA)!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am thrilled to announce a major milestone in my Linux journey: I have earned my &lt;strong&gt;Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA)&lt;/strong&gt; certification! This achievement has been a goal of mine for quite some time, and it reflects my deep passion for Linux, self-learning, and commitment to professional growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;RHCSA&lt;/strong&gt; certification is a hands-on, performance-based exam that pushes candidates to demonstrate their knowledge and skills in live, real-world scenarios. It’s designed to validate one’s ability to manage and configure Red Hat systems at a professional level, making it one of the most respected certifications in the industry. This wasn’t just an exam for me; it was a personal challenge to solidify my technical foundation and grow in my career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
